# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

#### FIROZ AL MAHMUD

House-803/1, Road-5, West Kazipara, Mirpur, Dhaka

Dhaka-1207

Contact: +88 01711054830 E-mail: fmahmud11@yahoo.com

### Career Objective:

I would like to work with an esteemed organization that would enable me to use my talent and skills which would provide excellent opportunities for career advancement and personal growth for me. I want to show my immense aspiration to become a quick learner and to prove myself as sincere and energetic person through extensive hard working with integrity that contributes to achieve the goals of organization.

#### Career Summary:

I am working as a Senior Officer at Aviva Finance Limited in business division. I worked at Standard Chartered Bank as Relationship Manager in payroll banking department. I have also experiences in different financial institutions with different role at corporate financial services as well as retail financial services division. I know client relationship management as well as portfolio financial management.

# **Employment History:**

# **Aviva Finance Limited**

Position : Senior Officer-(FT)

Department : Business

Duration : From 27<sup>th</sup> December 2020 To till.

Address : Sara Tower, 11/A toyenbee circular road, Motijheel , Dhaka- 1000

Major Duties : To develop business by maintaining client's information and team leading.

# **Standard Chartered Bank**

Position : Business Development Officer (Relationship Manager)-(FT)

Department : Payroll Banking

Duration : From 15<sup>th</sup> May 2018 To 28<sup>th</sup> February 2019 Address : 67 Gulshan Avenue, Gulshan, Dhaka-1212

Major Duties : To develop business by maintaining client's information in which acting as Relationship Manager.

#### **LankaBangla Finance Limited:**

Position : Team Leader - Officer - Senior Officer (FT)

Department : Corporate Financial Services

Duration : From 1st February 2015 to 30<sup>th</sup> April 2018 Address : 20 Kemal Ataturk Avenue, Banani, Dhaka-1213

Major Duties : Maintains Corporate Portfolio and build up relationship with corporate clients by analyzing financial status.

#### **United Finance Limited:**

Position : Associate-Group Leader (Part Time)

Department : Retail Financial Services

Duration : From 10<sup>th</sup> April 2010 To 10<sup>th</sup> March 2013

Address : Camellia House, 22 Kazi Nazrul Islam Avenue, Dhaka

Major Duties : Leading a team by hunting business and maintain relationship with clients by finding market information.

# Academic Qualification:

Exam Title	Concentration/Major	Institute	Result	Passing Year
CMA	Cost and Management Accounting	Institute of Cost and Management Accountant (ICMAB)	Professional Level	Running
MBA	Banking and Insurance	University of Dhaka	CGPA: 3.50 out of 4	2016
BBA	Finance	Asian Institute of Business and Technology	CGPA: 3.55 out of 4	2013
HSC	Humanities	Al Hera College	CGPA: 4.60 out of 5	2007
SSC	General	Pairkar Shah Jamalia Alim Madrasah	CGPA: 4.17 out of 5	2005

# **Training Summary:**

Training Title	Topic	Institute (Online)
Accounting	SSC,HSC,Basic Accounting	10 Minutes School
Accounting	IAS, IFRS	ICMAB
Accounting Software	Tally.ERP-9, SAP(FICO),QuickBooks,Wave & Xero	Online Platform

Training Title	Topic	Institute	Country	Location	Year	Duration
Development of professional selling	Customer services	BRIDDHI	Bangladesh	Six Season Hotel, Gulshan-2, Dhaka	2017	2 days

# Extra-Curricular Activities:

- ♣ Training on "Development of Professional Selling" conducted by BRIDDHI.
- ♣ Training on computer knowledge from "Youth Development Training Center".
- Having good knowledge on Internet.
- ♣ Participate in different cultural and sports activities in school and college level.
- 4 Debate, Public Speaking, Event Management, Customer Service, Business Development.

# **Achievements:**

- ♣ Top performer of the year 2015 in LankaBangla Finance and 2012 in United Finance.
- Winner of the special campaign arranged by the LankaBangla Finance Dhaka to Kathmandu in 2015.
- Winner of the campaign arranged by the LankaBangla Finance Dhaka to Indonesia in 2016.
- Certificate of Appreciation for the best performance in 2017.
- Scholarship for excellent result in HSC.

# Computer Skills:

- Operating Systems: Windows 10, 8, 7, Vista, XP.
- Graphics Design.
- ♣ Application Programs: Microsoft Word, Excel & PowerPoint.
- ♣ Internet: Have a good knowledge to communicate through Internet.

# Language Proficiency:

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Bangla	High	High	High
English	High	High	High
Arabic	Medium	Medium	Medium
Hindi	Low	Low	Medium

# Personal Details:

Father's Name : Late. Anowar Hossain Mother's Name : Rahima Khatun Date of Birth : April 12, 1989

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Bangladeshi
Religion : Islam

Permanent Address : Village-Pairkar, Post-Pairkar, P.S-Kahalu, Dist-Bogura

Current Location : Dhaka

# Reference (s):

Reference: 01 Reference: 02

Name : Ashfaqul Bari Tahmina Tawhid
Organization : Standard Chartered Bank Dhaka Bank Limited
Designation : Sr Manager Assistant Vice Presiden

Designation : Sr.Manager Assistant Vice President
Address : 67 Gulshan Avenue, Dhaka Cash Management Unit, Head office

Mobile : 01711451717 01709648364

E-Mail : ashfaqul.bari@sc.com tahmina.tawhid@dhakabank.com.bd Relation : Manager Sister

# Declaration:

I hereby, declare that the above furnished information is true and accurate.

<u>Signature:</u>